<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE helpmanual SYSTEM "../DTDs/manual.dtd">
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../xslt/helpmanual.xsl"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="../css/manual-oxygen.css"?>
<?altova_sps ..\DTDs\helpmanual.sps?>
<?altova_xslfo ..\xslt\helpmanualpdf.xslt?>
<helpmanual topicnumbers="yes">
    <front>
        <title>Helpmanual DTD</title>
        <author>Susan Bodnik</author>
        <version>1.1</version>
        <date>October 8, 2013</date>
        <preface>
            <p>This XML file contains examples of the elements that are available in the Helpmanual
                DTD. If you are not sure about an element in the Helpmanual DTD, you can consult
                this file to see examples of how to use the element.</p>
        </preface>
    </front>
    <topic id="viewingtags">
        <title>Author view</title>
        <body>
            <p>When you first open this document in OxygenXML, you will see the XML elements. You
                can see a WYSIWYG view of the XML file by clicking the Author tab in the lower left
                corner of the main content pane. This view will give you an approximate idea of what
                the document will look like after conversion to <b>HTML</b>. The WYSIWYG view uses a
                CSS style sheet to render the elements in &lt;oXygen> XML Editor.</p>
            <p>While you are working on your document, you will probably find it easier to work in
                    <indexterm>Tags On view</indexterm>, where you can clearly see the XML elements.
                To switch to Tags On view, select <b>
                    <indexterm>Author</indexterm> &gt; Tags with Attributes.</b>. You will then be
                able to easily add new elements. You can also switch to the different views
                available from the Author menu.</p>
            <p>Below you can see how this file displays in &lt;oXygen> XML Editor in Author view in
                    <i>No Tags</i> view and <i>Tags with attributes </i>view.</p>
            <fig>
                <figtitle>Tags with Attributes view </figtitle>
                <image alt="Tags On View" href="../Output/helpmanual/Images/tagson.gif"/>
            </fig>
            <fig>
                <figtitle>No Tags view </figtitle>
                <image alt="No Tags view" href="../Output/helpmanual/Images/tagsoff.gif"/>
            </fig>
        </body>
    </topic>
    <topic>
        <title>Front element</title>
        <body>
            <p>The front element Is the first element in the Helpmanual DTD. It contains the text
                that will display on the first page. </p>
            <p>The front element contains a required title element. Insert the title for your manual
                or report inside the title element. The front element also contains some optional
                elements:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>
                    <b>author</b>: The author of the document.</li>
                <li>
                    <b>version</b>: The version of the document.</li>
                <li>
                    <b>date</b>: The date the document was completed.</li>
                <li>
                    <b>preface</b>: The preface element contains one or more p elements. Each p
                    element contains a separate paragraph. You can use this element to add a brief
                    introduction to your report or manual.</li>
            </ul>
        </body>
    </topic>
    <topic id="topic">
        <title>Topic element</title>
        <body>
            <p>The primary element in the Helpmanual DTD is the topic element. When you write your
                report or manual, you will use a separate topic element for each concept, task, or
                topic. </p>
            <p>After you create your XML file, you will publish the file to HTML. The topic element
                generates a separate page when outputting to HTML, so after you publish your XML
                file you will have a set of linked HTML pages. </p>
            <p>If you want your content to display on a separate web page, you should insert a new
                topic element.</p>
            <p>The topic element contains the following elements:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>
                    <b><indexterm term.entry="title element, topic">title</indexterm>
                    </b>: The title element is required. Enter your page title in the title element.
                    When you insert a topic element, you will see a number inside the title element.
                    This numbering will help you to keep track of the order of the topics and the
                    ways that they are nested. Note that the numbering will display in the output by
                    default.</li>
                <li>
                    <b>body </b>- The body element is required. The body element contains the main
                    elements for the page - paragraphs, lists, tables, etc. </li>
                <li>
                    <b>related-links</b> - The related-links element is optional. You can use this
                    element to add a set of links to other topics.</li>
                <li>
                    <b>topic</b> - If you have a group of related topics, add a nested topic so that
                    they appear in the TOC as indented topics. Nested topics show the hierarchical
                    relationship in the table of contents.</li>
            </ul>
            <p>After you publish the XML file to HTML, you will see a Next and Previous navigation
                link in the upper right corner and lower right corner that links the topics.</p>
        </body>
        <related-links>
            <link id="bodyelement">Body element</link>
        </related-links>
        <topic id="nestedtopic">
            <title>Nested topics</title>
            <body>
                <p>This topic is nested inside its parent topic. In Author view, the title for each
                    topic level shows in a different font. The titles at the primary level show in a
                    blue font. The titles in nested topics show as a black font. Each level in the
                    hierarchy shows the topic title in a smaller font.</p>
                <section>
                    <title>Viewing nesting of topics</title>
                    <p>You can verify the nesting of the topics using the Outline pane. The Outline
                        pane shows you where you are in the hierarchy. In the graphic below, we can
                        see that there is a topic nested in the highlighted topic. Note that each
                        topic shows as indented when it is nested.</p>
                    <fig>
                        <image href="../Output/helpmanual/Images/outlinenesting.gif"
                            alt="Outline View"/>
                    </fig>
                    <p>You can also see where you are in the hierarchy by looking in the upper left
                        corner of the main Content pane. You will see there the path from the
                        document root to the current element. For example, if we look at the path
                        now, we can see that this element has the following path: </p>
                    <fig>
                        <image href="../Output/helpmanual/Images/breadcrumbs.gif" alt=""/>
                    </fig>
                    <p>Note how the current element has a blue line above it. In the graphic above,
                        we can see that the p element is inside the body element, the body element
                        is inside the topic element, the topic element is nested inside another
                        topic element, and the topic element is inside the helpmanual element.</p>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>Title numbering</title>
                    <p>By default, when you transform to HTML, numbering will display in the titles.
                        If you do not want the title numbers to display in the HTML output, you will
                        need to add an attribute to the helpmanual element. If you add the
                        topicnumbers attribute to the helpmanual element with a value of "no", the
                        title numbering will not display in the HTML output.</p>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>Linking to nested topics</title>
                    <p>You can automatically add links to nested topics. These links will display
                        only after you transform the XML file to HTML. If you want to display the
                        links to nested topics in the output, add the class attribute to the parent
                        topic element with a value of nestedtopiclinks. In the screenshot below, the
                        links to the nested topics at the bottom of the topic display after applying
                        the transformation in &lt;oXygen> XML Editor.</p>
                    <fig>
                        <image alt="Nested topic link"
                            href="../Output/helpmanual/Images/autotoc.jpg"/>
                    </fig>
                </section>
            </body>
        </topic>
    </topic>
    <topic class="nonestedtopiclinks" id="bodyelement">
        <title>Body element</title>
        <body>
            <p>The body element is located in the <indexterm>topic </indexterm>element. In the body
                element, you will find the main block level elements such as paragraphs, lists and
                images. The body element may contain the following elements, which can be inserted
                in any order:</p>
            <table width="600" border="1" cellpadding="5px" cellspacing="5px">
                <caption>Available block elements in the body element</caption>
                <tbody>
                    <tr align="center" valign="top">
                        <td>Element</td>
                        <td>Description</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>fig</td>
                        <td>A fig element contains an image, and an optional title and
                            description</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td align="left" valign="top" width="200px">p</td>
                        <td>A paragraph</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>ol</td>
                        <td>Numbered list</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>ul</td>
                        <td>Bullet list</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>lq</td>
                        <td>Long quote - displays in a separate paragraph</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>table</td>
                        <td>Table</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>note</td>
                        <td>Use to display cautions, notes, and tips.</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>dropdownlink</td>
                        <td>Use to create drop-down text that shows only when a link is clicked</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>section</td>
                        <td>If your topic contains subsections and titles, use the section
                            element</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>pre</td>
                        <td>A paragraph that shows the white space</td>
                    </tr>
                </tbody>
            </table>
        </body>
        <related-links>
            <link id="para">Paragraphs</link>
            <link id="notes">Notes</link>
            <link id="links">Drop-down links</link>
            <link id="figure">Figures</link>
            <link id="tables">Tables</link>
            <link id="blocklists">Lists</link>
            <link id="sections">Sections</link>
        </related-links>
        <topic id="para">
            <title>Paragraphs</title>
            <body>
                <p>To insert a paragraph, use the p element. Note that paragraphs cannot be nested -
                    you cannot insert a p tag inside a p tag. </p>
                <section>
                    <title>Long quotations</title>
                    <p>The lq element is a special type of paragraph that is used for long quotes.
                        The content of the lq element shows as indented on the left and right side.
                        Here is a quote from Online-learning.com&apos;s Professional XML Authoring
                        class:</p>
                    <lq>Document designers and authors are motivated to use XML because it provides
                        a means of describing documents, independent of medium. XML documents can be
                        used for print, the Web or any other document medium. This flexibility
                        encourages information system designers to use XML, as they can adopt one
                        set of standards, tools and methods for processing documents, regardless of
                        their various distribution targets.</lq>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>Pre element</title>
                    <p>The pre element preserves line breaks and white space, and it displays in a
                        fixed width font. The paragraph below uses the pre element. Note how the
                        text in the pre element shows the line breaks and white space:</p>
                    <pre>In normal paragraphs, line breaks and extra white space do not display. 
Empty spaces such as this space              are preserved in the pre element. 
Also, the line breaks are preserved in the pre element.
Note how the text inside this pre tag shows in a different font.</pre>
                </section>
            </body>
        </topic>
        <topic id="notes">
            <title>Notes and cautions</title>
            <body>
                <p>If you want to insert notes, tips or cautions, you can use the note tag. The note
                    tag has a <i>type</i> attribute with 3 possible values that specify the type of
                    note: <i>note, tip or caution</i>. </p>
                <p>When you add the type attribute, you will see that some text is added to the
                    beginning of the note. The text "Note:", "Tip:", or "Caution:" will be added to
                    the beginning. This will also appear in the HTML output files. </p>
                <note type="note"> This is a note type of note. </note>
                <note type="caution"> This is a caution type of note. </note>
                <note type="tip"> This is a tip type of note. </note>
                <p>After you apply the <xref id="stylesheet">stylesheets</xref>, you will see that
                    the appropriate text is added to the note - i.e. "Note", "Tip", or
                    "Caution".</p>
            </body>
        </topic>
        <topic id="links">
            <title>Drop-down links</title>
            <body>
                <p>Drop-down links allow you to compress related chunks of information in the same
                    topic. By using a drop-down link, you can present a much cleaner look by
                    displaying information only when the reader requests it.</p>
                <p>If you create an FAQ topic or a Troubleshooting topic, you might it useful to use
                    a drop-down link. If your topic contains a large number of FAQs or
                    troubleshooting tips, you will find that the use of drop-down links will make it
                    much easier for the user to locate information. In the example below, we present
                    a few FAQs.</p>
                <dropdownlink>
                    <linktext>How do I insert a drop-down link?</linktext>
                    <dropdowntext>
                        <p>To insert a drop-down link, insert the dropdownlink tag. The dropdownlink
                            tag contains two required elements: linktext and dropdowntext:</p>
                        <ul>
                            <li>
                                <b>linktext:</b> Insert a short phrase or sentence that describes
                                the information that will appear if the user clicks on the link. The
                                content of the linktext element will show as a weblink after
                                applying the stylesheets.</li>
                            <li>
                                <b>dropdowntext:</b> The content of this element will not initially
                                display when you view it in the browser after publishing your XML
                                file to HTML. The user will need to first click the link created by
                                the linktext element before seeing the content of the dropdowntext
                                element.</li>
                        </ul>
                    </dropdowntext>
                </dropdownlink>
                <dropdownlink>
                    <linktext>Are there other uses for drop-down links besides FAQs?</linktext>
                    <dropdowntext>
                        <p>Yes. You can use dropdown links wherever you want to show some content
                            only if the user clicks the link. For example, let&apos;s say you are
                            writing an online manual, and there are two different methods to
                            complete a specific task. You could insert two drop-down links for each
                            method.</p>
                    </dropdowntext>
                </dropdownlink>
            </body>
        </topic>
        <topic id="figure">
            <title>Figures</title>
            <body>
                <note>All images <b>must</b> be inserted into the Output/helpmanual/Images directory
                    inside your project directory. If you do not save your images in this directory,
                    the images will not display after the transformation. Below is a screenshot of
                    the directory that holds the images.</note>
                <fig>
                    <image href="../Output/helpmanual/Images/imagesfolder.png"
                        alt="Directory for Images"/>
                </fig>
                <p>You can insert a graphic using either the <indexterm>image element</indexterm> or
                    the fig element. The image element must be inserted inside a block element such
                    as a paragraph, while the fig element is inserted as a block level element,
                    outside of a paragraph. If you want your graphic to display on a separate line,
                    use the fig element.</p>
                <p>Below is a fig element. The fig element also can include an optional figtitle
                    (figure title) and an optional desc element (description of the figure).</p>
                <fig>
                    <figtitle>Figure title</figtitle>
                    <desc>Figure description</desc>
                    <image alt="This is a figure" href="../Output/helpmanual/Images/tulip2.jpg"/>
                </fig>
                <note>If you are working in a group and the other group members are using XMLSpy,
                    note that when you view XML files that were created in XMLSpy, you will not see
                    the images in OxygenXML in Author mode. Your group members will also not be able
                    to see your images when they open your XML file in XMLSpy. OxygenXML and XMLSpy
                    treat images a little differently in Authentic and Author modes. This will not
                    affect the images in the HTML output files. The images will display correctly
                    from XML files created in both XMLSpy and OxygenXML. </note>
                <p>The img element has 2 required attributes:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>href - This attribute points to the graphic file name. Use the following
                        format to insert the image: <i>../Output/helpmanual/Images/happy.gif. </i>
                        (Remember to also save your XML file in the OLL/Source folder.) As long as
                        you place your image first in the Output/helpmanual/Images directory inside
                        your project, the image will display inside &lt;oXygen> XML Editor.</li>
                    <li>alt - This attribute is a short description of the graphic.</li>
                </ul>
                <p>The image element also includes two optional attributes: width and height. You do
                    not need to include these attributes for HTML output. </p>
            </body>
            <related-links>
                <link id="inlinegraphics">Inline graphics</link>
            </related-links>
        </topic>
        <topic id="tables">
            <title>Tables</title>
            <body>
                <p>The table element allows you to present information in a table format. The tables
                    below use some of the available attributes to format the table.</p>
                <table width="550px" bgcolor="white" cellspacing="1" cellpadding="5" border="1">
                    <caption>Available elements in a table</caption>
                    <tbody>
                        <tr valign="middle" height="30px" align="center" bgcolor="silver">
                            <td>Elements </td>
                            <td>Description</td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr height="80px" align="left" bgcolor="white">
                            <td>paragraphs</td>
                            <td>
                                <p>This paragraph is inside a p tag.</p>
                                <p>This paragraph is inside a second p tag.</p>
                            </td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr bgcolor="#F2F2F2">
                            <td>images</td>
                            <td>
                                <p>You can insert an image using the image tag.</p>
                                <image alt="Table properties"
                                    href="../Output/helpmanual/Images/happy.gif"/>
                            </td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr bgcolor="white">
                            <td>lists</td>
                            <td>To insert a bullet list use the ul tag.<ul>
                                    <li>Item one</li>
                                    <li>Item two</li>
                                </ul></td>
                        </tr>
                    </tbody>
                </table>
                <section>
                    <title>Available attributes for tables</title>
                    <p>The table below lists the available attributes for a table. </p>
                    <p>Note that the table below is aligned to the center of the page by setting the
                        align property for the table element. </p>
                    <table align="center" cellspacing="2" border="1" width="500px">
                        <caption>Table attributes</caption>
                        <tbody>
                            <tr height="35px" bgcolor="lightgrey">
                                <td align="center">Element</td>
                                <td align="center">Available attributes</td>
                            </tr>
                            <tr>
                                <td align="center">table</td>
                                <td>
                                    <ul>
                                        <li>
                                            <b>width</b> - table width. Example: &lt;table
                                            width=&quot;500px&quot;&gt;</li>
                                        <li>
                                            <b>align:</b> Aligns the table to the left (default),
                                            center, or right.</li>
                                        <li>
                                            <b>border</b> - Specifies if the table shows a border.
                                            Example: &lt;table border=&quot;1&quot;&gt;</li>
                                        <li>
                                            <b>rules</b> - Specifies which rules (the lines in the
                                            table) should display. Example: &lt;table
                                            rules=&quot;rows&quot;&gt;</li>
                                        <li>
                                            <b>cellpadding</b> - Specifies the amount of space
                                            between the table cell wall and the table cell content.
                                            Example: &lt;table cellpadding=&quot;2px&quot;&gt;</li>
                                        <li>
                                            <b>cellspacing</b> - Specifies the amount of space
                                            around the table cell walls. Example: &lt;table
                                            cellspacing=&quot;5px&quot;&gt;</li>
                                        <li>
                                            <b>bgcolor</b> - Specifies the background color of a
                                            table row or table cell. Example: &lt;table
                                            bgcolor=&quot;lightgrey&quot;&gt;</li>
                                    </ul>
                                </td>
                            </tr>
                            <tr>
                                <td align="center">table row, table column, table cell</td>
                                <td>
                                    <ul>
                                        <li>
                                            <b>bgcolor</b> - Specifies the background color of a
                                            table row or table cell. Example: &lt;table
                                            bgcolor=&quot;lightgrey&quot;&gt;.</li>
                                        <li>
                                            <b>width</b> - Specifies the width of the table cell,
                                            column or row. If you specify the width for one table
                                            cell, all of the table cells in the same column will
                                            have the same width. Example: &lt;td
                                            width=&quot;50px&quot;&gt;.</li>
                                        <li>
                                            <b>height</b>: Specifies the height of a row or table
                                            cell. Example: &lt;tr height=&quot;40px&quot;&gt;.</li>
                                        <li>
                                            <b>align</b> - Specifies the alignment of the content of
                                            the table cell. Example: &lt;td
                                            align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;.</li>
                                        <li>
                                            <b>valign</b> - Specifies the vertical alignment of the
                                            content of the table cell. Example: &lt;td
                                            valign=&quot;middle&quot;&gt;.</li>
                                    </ul>
                                </td>
                            </tr>
                        </tbody>
                    </table>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>Table elements</title>
                    <table align="right" width="350px" bgcolor="white" cellspacing="1"
                        cellpadding="5" border="1">
                        <caption>Descriptions of table elements</caption>
                        <tbody>
                            <tr valign="middle" height="30px" align="center" bgcolor="silver">
                                <td width="112">Table Elements </td>
                                <td>Description</td>
                            </tr>
                            <tr bgcolor="white" align="left">
                                <td width="112">table</td>
                                <td>Each table goes in a table element.</td>
                            </tr>
                            <tr bgcolor="white" align="left">
                                <td width="112">tr</td>
                                <td>A row of table cells.</td>
                            </tr>
                            <tr bgcolor="white" align="left">
                                <td width="112">td</td>
                                <td>Each entry in your table goes inside a table cell.</td>
                            </tr>
                            <tr bgcolor="white" align="left">
                                <td>th</td>
                                <td>Table cell header</td>
                            </tr>
                        </tbody>
                    </table>
                    <p>The Table elements table uses an align attribute with a value of
                        &quot;right&quot;. If you align your table to the right, the text in the
                        elements below the table will wrap around the table rather than display
                        under the table (after you apply the transformation scenario).</p>
                </section>
            </body>
        </topic>
        <topic id="blocklists">
            <title>Lists</title>
            <body>
                <p>You can use two types of lists in the Helpmanual DTD.</p>
                <section>
                    <title>Numbered lists</title>
                    <p>Use the ol tag to create numbered lists. Note that each individual list item
                        in the list should be enclosed by an li tag.</p>
                    <ol>
                        <li>Step 1</li>
                        <li>Step 2</li>
                        <li>Step 3</li>
                    </ol>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>Bullet lists</title>
                    <p>Bullet lists use the ul tag. Like the ol tag, they also use the li tag for
                        each individual list item inside the list. You can specify the type of
                        bullet (circle, disc, or square) by specifying a value for the bullet
                        attribute of the ul tag</p>
                    <ul bullet="disc">
                        <li>Grapes</li>
                        <li>Bananas</li>
                        <li>Oranges</li>
                    </ul>
                </section>
            </body>
        </topic>
        <topic id="sections">
            <title>Sections</title>
            <body>
                <p>If you want to insert subtitles in your topic, you will need to first insert the
                    section element. The section element contains the same elements as the body
                    element such as paragraphs, lists, and tables. But it has an additional element
                    - the title element - that allows you to insert subtitles. If your topic
                    describes several concepts or tasks, use the section element to group each
                    concept or task.</p>
                <section>
                    <title>Section title</title>
                    <p>This paragraph appears inside a section element. Note how the title above
                        shows in a different font.</p>
                </section>
            </body>
        </topic>
    </topic>
    <topic class="nestedtopiclinks">
        <title>Inline elements</title>
        <body>
            <p>While a block element displays as a continuous block with a space above and below it,
                an inline element appears inside a block element. You can use inline elements to do
                things like format a word as bold or add a link to a website. The table below shows
                the inline elements that are available inside block elements such as paragraphs,
                lists, tables, and notes.</p>
            <table width="600" border="1" cellpadding="3" cellspacing="3">
                <tbody>
                    <tr align="center" valign="top">
                        <td>Element</td>
                        <td>Description</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>image</td>
                        <td>An image</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td align="left" valign="top" width="200px">q</td>
                        <td>An inline quotation</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>b</td>
                        <td>Bold text</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>i</td>
                        <td>Italic text</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>xref</td>
                        <td>Link to another topic</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>weblink</td>
                        <td>Link to a web page</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>mcomment</td>
                        <td>Used for marker's comments</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>comment</td>
                        <td>Used for internal comments - will not show in the HTML output</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>indexterm</td>
                        <td>Generates an index entry in the HTML output</td>
                    </tr>
                </tbody>
            </table>
        </body>
        <topic>
            <title>Comments</title>
            <body>
                <p>You can add two types of comments:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>comment - The comment element is used to insert a hidden comment. These
                        comments display in a red font in the Author view so that they are easier
                        to view. When you convert your XML file to HTML, the comment will be hidden.
                            <comment>This is a comment.</comment>
                    </li>
                    <li>mcomment - The mcomment element is used for marker&apos;s comments. These
                        comments display in a green font in the Author view. When your assignment
                        is submitted for marking, the marker will use this element to add comments.
                        You do not need to use this element in your assignments.<mcomment>
                            <p>This is a marker&apos;s comment.</p>
                        </mcomment>
                    </li>
                </ul>
            </body>
        </topic>
        <topic id="inlinegraphics">
            <title>Inline graphics</title>
            <body>
                <p>While the fig element displays an image as a block element on a separate line,
                    the image element can be used for inline graphics inside paragraphs, lists, and
                    tables.</p>
                <p>This inline image is nested inside a p tag. <image
                        href="../Output/helpmanual/Images/happy.gif" alt="happy gif"/> . </p>
                <p>The img element has 2 required attributes:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>href - This attribute points to the graphic file name. Use the following
                        format to insert the image: <i>../Output/helpmanual/Images/happy.gif </i> .
                        Always make sure that the href attribute for the image starts with
                            <i>../Output/helpmanual/Images/</i>, followed by the name of the graphic
                        file. Do not use an absolute path to the graphic, such as
                        c:/oll/Output/helpmanual/happy.gif. If you use an absolute path to the
                        graphic (a path that points to a directory on your computer), then the
                        graphic will not display after transforming to HTML.</li>
                    <li>alt - This attribute is a short description of the graphic.</li>
                </ul>
                <p>
                    <image alt="Table properties"
                        href="../Output/helpmanual/Images/outlinenesting.gif"/> Note how this
                    paragraph contains a large image inside a paragraph that also contains text. The
                    large image affects the text that is on the same line as the image. If you want
                    to insert a large graphic, insert the figure element so that the graphic
                    displays on a separate line.</p>
                <note>All images <b>must</b> be saved in the Output/helpmanual/Images directory
                    inside your project directory. If you do not save your images in this directory,
                    the images will not display after the transformation. Below is a screenshot of
                    the directory that holds the images.</note>
                <fig>
                    <image href="../Output/helpmanual/Images/imagesfolder.png"
                        alt="Directory for Images"/>
                </fig>
            </body>
        </topic>
        <topic id="inlinelinks">
            <title>Links</title>
            <body>
                <p>You can insert links inside paragraphs, lists, and tables. Several types of links
                    are available, including web links, links between topics, and glossary
                    links.</p>
                <section>
                    <title>Web links</title>
                    <p>Use the <indexterm>weblink element</indexterm> to create a <weblink
                            href="http://www.online-learning.com">link to a Web site</weblink>. The
                        weblink element has a required attribute:<i> href</i>. Enter the website URL
                        in the <i>href </i>attribute. </p>
                    <note type="caution"> Make sure that you include http:// at the beginning of the
                        URL.</note>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>Links between topics</title>
                    <p>Use the xref element to link to another topic. The url of the xref element
                        should be the same as the id attribute of the topic you are linking to. </p>
   <p>In the example below, a topic element has an id attribute with a value of
                        &quot;topic2&quot;. The p tag below is located in another topic element. The
                        xref tag has an id attribute of &quot;topic2&quot;. After the XML file is
                        published to HTML, the content in the xref tag will link to the first topic
                        below.</p>
                    <pre>&lt;topic id=&quot;topic2&quot;&gt;... &lt;/topic&gt; 
						
&lt;topic>&lt;title>Second topic>&lt;/title>&lt;body>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;xref id=&quot;topic2&quot;&gt;Link to topic 2&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/body>&lt;/topic> </pre>
                    <p>The links below use the xref tag and they link to a topic that uses the same
                        id attribute:</p>
                    <p>
                        <xref id="viewingtags">Authentic view </xref> - This first link has an id
                        attribute of "viewingtags". This means that after we transform the XML
                        document, a link will be created that links to the topic that also has an id
                        attribute of "viewingtags".</p>
                    <p>
                        <xref id="topic">Topic element </xref> - This second link has an id
                        attribute of "topic". This means that after we transform the XML document, a
                        link will be created that links to the topic that also has an id attribute
                        of "topic".</p>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>Glossary links</title>
                    <p>You may also use the xref element to link to a glossary definition. To link
                        to a glossary definition, you must first enter the glossary term in the
                        glossary element. Each individual glossary term needs an id attribute so
                        that you can link to it. </p>
                    <p>In the example below, the glossary contains a definition for the term
                        &quot;topic&quot;. The glossentry element has an id attribute with a value
                        of &quot;topicid&quot;. The xref tag below points to the glossary definition
                        by using the value of the id attribute of the glossary definition. The
                        content of the xref tag will display as a link to the glossary definition
                        after publishing the XML file to HTML.</p>
                    <pre>&lt;glossary&gt;
  &lt;glossentry id=&quot;topicid&quot;&gt;&lt;glossterm&gt;topic&lt;/glossterm&gt;
    &lt;glossdef&gt;A topic contains information on one task or concept.&lt;/glossdef&gt;
 &lt;/glossentry&gt;
&lt;/glossary&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The primary element in the Helpmanual DTD is the 
&lt;xref id=&quot;topicid&quot;&gt;topic&lt;/xref&gt; element.&lt;/p&gt;</pre>
                    <p>This links to the <xref id="url">URL</xref> glossary definition.</p>
                </section>
            </body>
            <related-links>
                <link id="links">Drop-down links</link>
            </related-links>
        </topic>
        <topic>
            <title>Bold and Italics</title>
            <body>
                <p>You can use the b, i, and q elements to apply formatting to letters, words, or
                    phrases.</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>
                        <b>b </b>- The b element formats text as <b>bold text.</b>.</li>
                    <li>
                        <b>i </b>- The i element formats text as <i>italic text</i>.</li>
                    <li>
                        <b>q </b>- You can use the q element for <q>inline quotes</q>.</li>
                </ul>
            </body>
        </topic>
        <topic>
            <title>Index </title>
            <body>
                <p>The style sheets create an index using the words or phrases that are marked up
                    inside the content of the XML file. To add an entry to the index, insert an
                    indexterm element inside a paragraph, list, or table. </p>
                <p>In this paragraph, we have included two entries in the index:
                        <indexterm>indexterm</indexterm> and <indexterm>Creating an
                        index</indexterm>. Note that each phrase is located inside an indexterm
                    element. If you <weblink href="indexpage.html">view the index</weblink>, you
                    will see an entry for each index term that links back to this page.</p>
                <section>
                    <title>Modifying the entry in the index</title>
                    <p>You may want to change the text that appears in an index entry . For example,
                        let's say that you wanted to add an index entry for <indexterm>adding a
                            topic</indexterm>. But you wanted the text "Topic, adding" to display in
                        the index. You could do this by adding a term.entry attribute as below:</p>
                    <pre>&lt;indexterm term.entry="Topic, adding">adding a topic&lt;/indexterm></pre>
                    <p>When you add the term.entry attribute to the indexterm element above, the
                        text "Topic, adding" will display in the index.</p>
                </section>
            </body>
        </topic>
    </topic>
    <topic>
        <title>Related links</title>
        <body>
            <p>If you want to add a group of links to the bottom of the topic, you can insert the
                related-links element. The related-links element contains one or more link elements.
                Each link element has an id attribute. The id attribute of the link element points
                to the topic that you are linking to. </p>
            <p>When you insert the related-links element, a link element will display. To add an
                additional link element in Author view, you can just hit Enter on the keyboard and
                choose the link element.</p>
        </body>
        <related-links>
            <link id="inlinelinks">Links</link>
        </related-links>
    </topic>
    <topic>
        <title>Bibliography element</title>
        <body>
            <p>If you want to add a bibliography, insert the biblio element inside the back
                element.</p>
            <p>The biblio element can contain one or more custmbib elements. Enter each
                bibliographic entry inside a custmbib element. </p>
            <note type="note">When you insert the biblio element, the page title for the
                bibliography page is automatically inserted.</note>
        </body>
    </topic>
    <topic>
        <title>Glossary element</title>
        <body>
            <p>If you want to add a glossary, insert the glossary element inside the back
                element.</p>
            <p>The glossary element can contain one or more glossentry elements. Enter each glossary
                entry inside a glossentry element. The glossentry element has 2 child elements:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>
                    <b>glossterm</b>: The glossary term. </li>
                <li>
                    <b>glossdef:</b> The glossary definition</li>
            </ul>
            <p>The glossentry element has an optional id attribute. Use the id attribute if you want
                to link to the glossary definition from another topic element.</p>
            <note type="note">When you insert the glossary element, the page title for the glossary
                page is automatically inserted.</note>
        </body>
    </topic>
    <back>
        <biblio>
            <custmbib>
                <p>
                    <weblink href="http://www.online-learning.com">Online-learning.com</weblink>
                </p>
            </custmbib>
            <custmbib>
                <p>Another bibliographic entry.</p>
            </custmbib>
        </biblio>
        <glossary>
            <glossentry id="stylesheet">
                <glossterm>stylesheet</glossterm>
                <glossdef>A CSS or XSLT stylesheet. A stylesheet determines the format of an
                    element. For example, you can specify that an element should be bold or it
                    should display with as a bullet list. </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="topicid">
                <glossterm>topic</glossterm>
                <glossdef>A topic contains information on one task or concept. </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="nestedtopicid">
                <glossterm>Nested Topic</glossterm>
                <glossdef>A nested topic is inside another topic. </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="url">
                <glossterm>URL</glossterm>
                <glossdef>Uniform Resource Locator. Specifies the location of a specific resource. A
                    URL is divided into several parts. 1. The resource type - A web link uses the
                    http:// to indicate a website. 2. The domain name - This is the name of the
                    domain. An example is www.online-learning.com. 3. The file path - if you are
                    linking to a specific page in a website, you can include the name of the file.
                    For example: links.html. An example of a complete URL is
                        <i>http://www.online-learning.com/contact.html.</i>
                </glossdef>
            </glossentry>
            <glossentry id="transformations">
                <glossterm>transformations</glossterm>
                <glossdef>When you apply an XSLT style sheet to an XML file, you are transforming
                    the XML file to another format. This is called a transformation. Often you will
                    transform the XML file to HTML, but you might also transform to other formats
                    such as PDF or RTF format.</glossdef>
            </glossentry>
        </glossary>
    </back>
</helpmanual>
